{"id":"2018_7","name":"","memoryVerse":"“The women said to Naomi: ‘Praise be to the LORD, who this day has not left you without a guardian-redeemer. May he become famous throughout Israel!’ ” – Ruth 4:14","dayQuestions":{"one":{"title":"FIRST DAY: Read the notes and the references.","questions":[{"id":"2018_7_1","questionText":"1. Use this space to record how you have seen God’s activity during the week. (How has He provided, answered, comforted, reconciled, guided, etc.?)","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_7_2","questionText":"2. What from the notes, lecture, group sharing or personal study impacted you most in the past week?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"two":{"title":"SECOND DAY: Read 1 Samuel 1.\nChapter 1 focuses on God’s gracious response to an Israelite woman enduring great disappointment.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"1:1-28"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_7_3","questionText":"3. What was Hannah’s situation at home, and how did she handle it?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_7_4","questionText":"4. What lessons can you learn from Eli’s interaction with Hannah? How might you apply those lessons in your life?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_7_5","questionText":"5. How does Hannah’s response reveal her faith and love for God? What challenges you personally from Hannah’s example?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"three":{"title":"THIRD DAY: Read 1 Samuel 2:1-11.\nHannah offered Samuel to the Lord and responded with rejoicing and prayer.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"2:1-11"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_7_6","questionText":"6. What do you learn about God’s character and work from Hannah’s prayer? How does this help you in your present circumstances?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_7_7","questionText":"7. Who else in Scripture was willing to sacrifice their son for God’s glory? What are you willing to sacrifice in order to bring glory to God? (Use any scripture reference.)","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_7_8","questionText":"8. What does Hannah’s prayer reveal about God’s future plans?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"four":{"title":"FOURTH DAY: Read 1 Samuel 2:12-36.\nChapters 2-3 reveal a contrast between Eli’s family and Samuel.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"2:12-36"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_7_9","questionText":"9. Describe the sins of Eli’s sons and Eli’s response to their sin. (See also Leviticus 7:28-36.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Leviticus","verse":"7:28-36"}]},{"id":"2018_7_10","questionText":"10. What did God promise would happen to Eli’s family because of their unwillingness to repent?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_7_11","questionText":"11. What behaviors (of yours or of others close to you) are you tempted to ignore or enable? How is God inviting you to respond?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"five":{"title":"FIFTH DAY: Read 1 Samuel 3.\nGod spoke and revealed His plans through Samuel.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"3:1-21"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_7_12","questionText":"12. What stands out to you about God’s interactions with Samuel and Samuel’s interactions with Eli?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_7_13","questionText":"13. What does this chapter reveal about the privilege and the responsibility of being the Lord’s servant?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_7_14","questionText":"14. What has God revealed to you in His Word? How can you make known God’s Word to others?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"six":{"title":"SIXTH DAY: Review 1 Samuel 1-3.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"1:1-3:21"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_7_15","questionText":"15. What attribute of God resonated most from your study of this week’s passage? How do you see that attribute displayed in the world today?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]}}}